Sheila Guard 23723 – 23<sup>rd</sup> AVE SE Bothell, WA 98021 sguard@isomedia.com

April 24, 2009

To: Washington Science Olympiad

Please accept this letter of intent to run for a position on the Washington State Science Olympiad Board. I accept the nomination and agree to represent the Science Olympiad program to the best of my abilities.

I have enclosed a copy of my current resume for consideration. Of note, I have participated in the Science Olympiad program since 1993, working both in the Middle and Senior High School divisions, as well as assisting in the organization of invitational and regional tournaments.

I look forward to working with this esteemed group in the advancement of the Washington State Science Olympiad program.

Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

Sheila Guard Science Teacher & Coach, Canyon Park Junior High & Bothell High School Page Two Sheila Guard

# Sheila Guard

23723 23<sup>rd</sup> AVE SE, Bothell, WA 98021 (425) 408-6336– <u>sguard@isomedia.com</u>

### **EDUCATION**

City University, Bellevue, Washington
Master of Education in Instructional Technology, 2001
University of Washington, Seattle, Washington
Teacher Certification Program (TEP), 1991
Bachelor of Arts in Zoology, 1990

### **CERTIFICATION**

National Board Certification, November, 2005
Certification Area: Science/Early Adolescence
Washington State Continuing Teaching Certificate, 4-12
Endorsement areas: Biology, General Sciences, Health, Instructional Technology, Mathematics

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

1992-present Northshore School District Bothell, WA
Canyon Park Junior High, 1994-present

Northshore Junior High, 1992-1994

## Science Teacher

- Science Olympiad Coach, Grades 5-12, 1993-Present
- Experience teaching Math, Life, Physical and Earth Sciences to 7th, 8th and 9th graders.

Seattle, WA

- Science Department Chair, 1998-2004.
- Building staff development chair, 1996 2000.

# 1990-1991 University of Washington

# Student Teaching

- Biology, Shorewood High School, Shoreline School District, 9/90-6/91
- General Science, Kellogg Middle School, Shoreline School District, 3/91-6/91

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT/HONORS

## **District Committees:**

- TARC, Teaching & Assessment Research Committee: Junior High representative, 2000 to present
- Served on a district-wide science articulation committee, 1994 2004 (Chair, 1998-2002).
- Culminating Exhibition Team: Prepared requirements for graduation research project, 2002-2004
- District Science Safety Team: Established safety standards, including a Chemical Hygiene Plan, 2004

## Leadership Experiences:

- Washington State Science Olympiad Board member, 2008-present
- 2008 OEST Washington State Geology Teacher of the Year
- 2007-08 Northshore Teacher of the Year
- 2007 AMGEN Award Winner for Science Teaching Excellence (A.A.S.T.E.)
- Northwest Region Science Olympiad Board Chair, 2006-present
- Lead teacher with the N.S.F. Systemic Middle School Science Grant, 5-District Curriculum team (now part of the Institute for Systems Biology education research department), 1998-present
- Earned a Washington Initiative Scholarship in 2004 to pursue National Board Certification
- Northwest Region Local Exhibits Coordinator for the 2004 NSTA Convention in Seattle
- Earned Seattle Pacific University Mathematics in Teaching scholarship for graduate work, 1992
- Member of National Science Teacher's Association and Washington Science Teacher's Association